Preliminary Guide to the Lightning Brown Papers, 1983-1985
Lightning Brown papers 1983-1985
Brown, Lightning
3.00 Linear Feet 1500 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Lightning Brown Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1999.
Biographical Note
Gay rights activist and the first openly gay candidate for public office in North Carolina, resident of Chapel Hill (Orange Co.), N.C.
Collection Overview
Collection contains materials primarily related to the 1984 elections. They include correspondence with public officials (among others), articles, and studies. The materials reflect Brown's interest and involvement in the Democratic Party, national legislation, and issues regarding gay rights.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Gay rights -- United States
Elections -- North Carolina
Gay activists -- North Carolina
Homosexuality -- Law and legislation -- United States
Orange County (N.C.) -- History
Orange County (N.C.) -- Politics and government
Gays -- Legal status, laws, etc.--United States
Contents of Collection
- Accession 2000-0125
  - Apr. 1984 - Dec. 1984 (Box 1)
  - Mar. 1983 - Feb. 1985
  - Feb. 1984 - Mar. 1985
  - May 1984 - June 1984
  - May 1984
  - Jan. 1984 - Mar. 1984
  - Dec. 1984 - Feb. 1985
  - Feb. 1984 - Oct. 1984
  - Oct. 1984 - Dec. 1984
  - Oct. 1984
  - July 1984 - Nov. 1984 (Box 2)
  - Jan. 1983 - Apr. 1984
  - Dec. 1983 - Aug. 1984
  - Mar. 1984 - Nov. 1984
  - Jan. 1984 - Aug. 1984
  - June 1984 - Dec. 1984